coventry.ac.uk 2018-12-05

# Privacy Policy | Coventry University

##### Purpose

Coventry University Group is committed to protecting and respecting your privacy.

This policy (together with any other documents referred to in it) sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to use, will be processed by us. Please read the following carefully so as to understand our views and practices regarding personal data and how we will treat it.

Coventry University group is made up of a number different legal entities full details of which can be found here. This privacy notice is issued on behalf of Coventry University group so when we mention Coventry University, we, us or our in this privacy notice, we are referring to the relevant company in the Coventry University group responsible for processing your personal data. We will let you know which entity will be the controller for your data when you engage with us.

For the purpose of the General Data Protection Regulation 2016, and any and all other applicable laws and regulations relating to the processing of personal data and privacy (the "Data Protection Legislation"), Coventry University of Priory Street, Coventry, United Kingdom, CV1 5FB is the Data Controller (ICO registration number Z6939585) in respect of this website. Coventry University’s Data Protection Officer can be contacted by emailing [enquiry.ipu@coventry.ac.uk](mailto:enquiry.ipu@coventry.ac.uk).

##### The Policy

**INFORMATION WE MAY COLLECT FROM YOU**

We will only collect personally identifiable information (such as your name, address and contact details) or such other information as may be listed in the relevant data collection form, via the Coventry University Website when it is voluntarily submitted by you to us. We may collect and process the following data about you for the purposes specified:

  * Personal details given to us by you via on-line forms will be used to provide you with information, goods or services you have requested, such as course brochures or prospectuses. The details you provide will not be used for marketing purposes unless you have been informed of this and have expressly consented to  having your details used for this purpose;
  * Information provided by you via feedback forms or questionnaires will be used in our legitimate interest so to improve our site;
  * Information provided by you when reporting a fault with the Coventry University Website will be used for the purposes of rectifying that fault in accordance with the legitimate interests of Coventry University;
  * If you contact us we may keep a record of that correspondence so as to deal with and/or respond to that correspondence as is necessary for the performance of any contract with you or in order to take step at your request prior to the entering into of a contract and/or where such processing is in the legitimate interests of Coventry University;
  * Personal data provided as part of any online application process for an employment opportunity shall be processed so as to allow us to process and evaluate the merits of that application in accordance with our legitimate interests;

We may also use personal data which you provide to us in any of the ways listed above and in the following ways:

  * To deal with and/or respond to any enquiry or request made by you prior to entering into any contract or agreement with Coventry  University or as a result of such contract or agreement ;
  * To ensure that content on the Coventry University Website is presented in the most effective manner for you and your computer in accordance with our legitimate interests;
  * To carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us;
  * To allow you to participate in interactive features of the Coventry University Website, if/when you choose to do so whether this be prior to you entering into any contract or agreement with the University or as a result of the same;
  * To comply with a legal obligation to which Coventry University to subject;
  * To notify you about any changes to Coventry University or the courses or services offered where it is in our legitimate interests to do so and where you have expressed an interest in the same previously or where such notification is required so as to allow us to perform any contractual agreement with you or where you have expressly opted in to receiving such communications.

If you do not want us to use your personal data in any of the ways set out above you can opt out of receiving communications from us at any time thereafter by clicking the “unsubscribe” or “opt out” link in any such communications.

We may also collect, use and share Aggregated Data such as statistical or demographic data for any purpose. Aggregated Data may be derived from your personal data but is not considered personal data in law as this data does not directly or indirectly reveal your identity. For example, we may aggregate your Usage Data to calculate the percentage of users accessing a specific website feature. However, if we combine or connect Aggregated Data with your personal data so that it can directly or indirectly identify you, we treat the combined data as personal data which will be used in accordance with this privacy notice.

**RETENTION OF PERSONAL DATA**

We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements.

To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.

**IP ADDRESSES AND COOKIES**

Information about your computer including logging information, such as your machine's IP address, operating system and browser type, may be collected automatically by the server and used for system administration and statistical purposes only. This is statistical data about the browsing actions and patterns of users of Coventry University’s website, and does not identify any individual.

Cookies may be used to collect user data to enhance your experience of the Coventry university Website. For example, we may use cookies to determine whether your browser can accept a particular type of software, or to stop pop-up boxes appearing each time you visit the Coventry University Website. We may use cookies for other purposes in the future, as the Coventry University Website develops and this statement will be amended to reflect any such changes. Further details of our policy in relation to cookies can be [found in our Cookie Policy](https://www.coventry.ac.uk/legal-documents/cookie-policy/).

**WHERE WE STORE YOUR PERSONAL DATA**

The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area (“EEA”). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers. Such staff may be engaged in, among other things, the fulfilment of our contracts and/or agreements with you, the processing of any payments and the provision of support services. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storage and processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy and that it is subject to appropriate safeguards.

All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access specific parts of the Coventry University Website, you are responsible for keeping that password confidential. We ask you not to share your password with anyone.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your personal data transmitted to our site; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information we will use strict procedures and security features to try and prevent unauthorised access.

**DISCLOSURE OF YOUR INFORMATION**

Information about you will only be disclosed to relevant employees of Coventry University, and will not be revealed to third parties outside Coventry University Group unless we are under a legal duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce any agreements which may be entered into between us; or to protect the rights, property or safety of Coventry University, its students, staff or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud prevention and credit risk reduction.

**YOUR RIGHTS**

You have the right to:

**Request access to your personal data** (commonly known as a "data subject access request"). This enables you to receive a copy of the personal data that we hold about you and to check that we are lawfully processing it.

**Request correction** of the personal data that we hold about you. This enables you to have any incomplete or inaccurate data that we hold about you corrected, although we may need to verify the accuracy of the new personal data that you provide to us.

**Request erasure** of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to delete or remove personal data where there is no good reason for us continuing to process it. You also have the right to ask us to delete or remove your personal data where you have successfully exercised your right to object to processing (see below), where we may have processed your personal data unlawfully or where we are required to erase your personal data to comply with local law. Please note, however, that we may not always be able to comply with your request of erasure for specific legal reasons which will be notified to you, if applicable, at the time of your request.

**Object to processing** of your personal data where we are relying on a legitimate interest (or those of a third party) and there is something about your particular situation which makes you want to object to processing on this ground as you feel it impacts on your fundamental rights and freedoms. You also have the right to object where we are processing your personal data for direct marketing purposes. In some cases, we may demonstrate that we have compelling legitimate grounds to process your personal data which override your rights and freedoms.

**Request restriction of processing** of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to suspend the processing of your personal data in the following scenarios: (a) if you want us to establish the data's accuracy; (b) where our use of the data is unlawful but you do not want us to erase it; (c) where you need us to hold the data even if we no longer require it as you need it to establish, exercise or defend legal claims; or (d) you have objected to our use of your data but we need to verify whether we have overriding legitimate grounds to use it.

**Request the transfer** of your personal data to you or to a third party. We will provide to you, or a third party you have chosen, your personal data in a structured, commonly used, machine-readable format. Note that this right only applies to automated information which you initially provided consent for us to use or where we used the information to perform a contract with you.

**Withdraw consent** at any time where we are relying on consent to process your personal data. However, this will not affect the lawfulness of any processing carried out before you withdraw your consent. If you withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide certain products or services to you. We will advise you if this is the case at the time you withdraw your consent.  You can ask us to stop sending you marketing messages at any time by following the “unsubscribe” (or similar) links on any marketing message sent to you or by contacting us at any time.  Where you opt out of receiving these marketing messages, this will not apply to personal data provided to us as a result of a purchase, product/service experience or other transactions.

If you wish to exercise any of your above rights, please send a written request to Information Protection Unit, Coventry University, Portal House, 163 New Union Street, Coventry, CV1 2PL or email [enquiry.ipu@coventry.ac.uk](mailto:enquiry.ipu@coventry.ac.uk).

You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data or to exercise any of your other rights. However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive.  Alternatively, we may refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances.

We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access your personal data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response.

We try to respond to all legitimate requests within one month. Occasionally it may take us longer than a month if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, we will notify you and keep you updated. The Coventry University Website may, from time to time, contain links to and from external websites as a service to our visitors.  If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies.  Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.  The provision of a link on our site to an external website should not be taken as an endorsement by Coventry University of that external website, its owners or their products/services.

**CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY**

Any changes we may make to our privacy policy in the future will be posted on this page.

**COMPLAINTS**

If you are unhappy with the way in which we have collected or processed your personal data or have any other complaint in relation to our handling of your personal data you can contact our Data Protection Officer by writing to, Information Protection Unit, Coventry University, Portal House, 163 New Union Street, Coventry, CV1 2NT or email [enquiry.ipu@coventry.ac.uk](mailto:enquiry.ipu@coventry.ac.uk)  

You also have a right to  make a complaint to the Information Commissioner, further information can be found on the Information Commissioner’s website at www.ico.org.uk or via their helpline on 0303 123 1113.
